Finding Aid for the Paul Jordan Smith Papers LSC.0267
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul Jordan Smith papers
1909-1971
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jordan-Smith, Paul, 1885-1971
LSC.0267
27.0 Linear Feet (54 boxes and 1 oversize box)
Paul Jordan Smith (1885-1971) was a journalist, editor, and bibliofile. The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts of articles, books, and book reviews, lectures and teaching materials, notes on Robert Burton, poems, inscribed books, collected literary articles, clippings, bookplates, portraits, memorabilia, and contracts with publishers.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul Jordan Smith.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9919729323606533
Biography
Born in 1885, Paul Jordan Smith was a journalist, editor, and bibliofile; his novel, Nomad, was published in 1925; with Floyd Dell, translated and edited Robert Burton's Anatomy of Melancholy (1927); wrote a book column for the Los Angeles Times, and served as literary editor from 1933-1957; he died on June 17, 1971 in Los Angeles.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts of articles, books, and book reviews, lectures and teaching materials, notes on Robert Burton, poems, material relating to Paul Jordan Smith artwork, books inscribed to Paul Jordan Smith, collected literary articles, clippings, bookplates, portraits, memorabilia, and contracts with publishers.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence (Boxes 1-24).
Manuscripts (Boxes 25-43).
Books (Box 43).
Ephemera (Boxes 44-45).
Personal material (Box 46).
Memorabilia (Box 47).
Additions (Boxes 48-55).
Manuscripts for publication; American literature -- 20th century.; Journalists; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Jordan-Smith, Paul, 1885-1971 -- Archives
- Correspondence
  - A - Ak
    - Adams, Agnes A., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, Charles K., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951., 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Adams, George Matthew, 1878-., 11 items. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adams, George Matthew., 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Aikman, Duncan, 1889-., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ainslie, Douglas, 1865-1948., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Al
    - Alger, Philip L., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Allen, Arthur A., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Allen, Dexter., 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Allen, Raymond Bernard, 1902-., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Am
    - Ament, Eleanor and Will S., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Arts Foundation., 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Association on Emeritii., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - American Book Collector., 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Confederacy for Democracy., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - American Library Association., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - An
    - Anderson, Marcia Crary., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anderson, Rita., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Anderson & Ritchie., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Andrews, Robert Douglas, 1903-., 6 items. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Angel, Jennifer & Ronald., 10 items. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Ap - Arl
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Incorporated., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Arden Hotel., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Arellanos, Audrey., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Arensberg, Walter Conrad, 1878-1954., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Argus Book Shop., 12 items. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Arlott, John., 5 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Arm - Art
    - Armour, Richard Willard, 1906-., 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Armstrong, James R., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Arnold, Julian Biddulph, 1863-., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Arnow, Harriette Louisa (Simpson), 1908-., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Arthur Machen Society Newsletter., 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arv - Au
    - Arvidson, Lloyd A., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Associated Merchandising Corporation., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Audrain, F.W., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Auslander, Joseph, 1897-., 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Authors Club., 7 items. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Av
    - Averbuch, Bernard., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Avram, Rachmael Ben., 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ba
    - Babb, Lawrence., 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Babb, Stanley E., 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Babcock, Frederic & Helen R., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Baker, Howard, 1905-., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ballin, Hugo, 1879-1956., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bar - Bax
    - Barish, Mildred., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Barker, George M., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Barlone, Commandant D., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Barnes, Delphine D., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - A.N. Barnes & Company., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bartlett, Elizabeth., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Batey, Maggie Jordan., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bathhurst, Diana., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Batten, Barton, Durstine & Company Incorporated., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Baxter Frères Book Publishers., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bay - Bea
    - Baylor, Robert E., 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Beach's Bookshop., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Beale, Will., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Beaman, Alexander Gaylord, 1885-., 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bea - Beg
    - Bean, William B., M.D., 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bear, Mary M., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bedborough, George W., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Bedford Hotel., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bel - Bi
    - Bell, W.D., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bellman, Samuel I., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Benthe, Laurel., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bergenthal, Erling., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bernard, Robert J., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Beverly Hills Unified School District., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Beymer, William Gilmore., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bickers, Sheridan., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Biddle, George., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Billings, Millard F., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Binns, Katherine A., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bell, Alphonzo., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Belt, Elmer, 1893-., 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bensley, Edward., 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bentley, Phyllis Eleanor, 1894-., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Berry, John., 5 items. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Bevis, Leura Dorothy., 3 items. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Birely, Jean H., 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Birely, Jean H., 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bl
    - Black, John., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Blackman, Robert., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Blake, James D., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bloch, Henry., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Blondin family., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Bo
    - Bodley Book Shop., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bogart, Laura Gertrude., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Books & Authors., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bowler, Alida., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bowman, John Clarke., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Boyd, Aubrey., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bodeen, DeWitt., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Booth, Bradford Allen, 1909-., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Borough, Reuben W., 1883-., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Bottome, Phyllis, 1884-., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Bradbury, Ray, 1920-., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bra - Bri
    - Bradley, John Hodgdon., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bradley, Preston., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Brasfield, E.D., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Braun, Irwin H., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Brenton, Thaddeus R., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bretnor, Reginald., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Brickell, Herschel, 1889-., 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Brier, Royce., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Briggs, Kathleen., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Briggs, Leah., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - British Museum., 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Bristow, Gwen, 1903-., 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, n.d.-1954.; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1955.; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1956-1959.; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1960.; 7 items. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1960.; 10 items. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1961.; 6 items. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Broadcast Music Incorporated, 1962-1963.; 9 items. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Bro - Bry
    - Brolley, A.S., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bromson, Ada Meade., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brown, Elwood., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brown, William Thurston., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brownson, Roswell & Ada., 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bruce, Stewart E., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Bryan, Charles V., 2 items. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Brown, Neal., 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Browne, Lewis, 1897-., 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Bu - Bur
    - Buchanan, Russell A., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Buck, Mitchell S., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Budge, E. Wallis., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Burbank Public Library., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Burke-Morrow, Marcella., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Buck, Pearl (Sydenstricker), 1892-., 3 items. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Burnett, William Riley, 1899-., 5 items. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie (Thomson) Harding, 1882-., n.d.-1962.; 10 items. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1962.; 8 items. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1966.; 11 items. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1967.; 7 items. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1967.; 9 items. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1968.; 12 items. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Burton, Ruth Guthrie, 1969.; 11 items. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Bus
    - Bussell, Mrs. Ruby Weyburn., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Butler, Paul G., 1 item. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Business., 4 items. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ca - Cal
    - Cajori, Florian., 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Caledonian Station Hotel., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - California Federation of Chaparral Poets., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - California State Library., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - California Writers Guild., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Calverton, V.F., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958., 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cahill, Holger., 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Caldwell, Taylor (pseudonym)., 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - California, University of., 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - California, University of., 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Cam - Cap
    - Camp, Eleanor., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Campbell, Kay., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Camp, William Martin., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, Lily Bess, 1883-., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Campbell, Robert., 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Candlelight Press., 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Cantwell, Robert, 1908-., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 11a)
  - Car
    - Carew, Harold D., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carl Sandburg's 75th Birthday [Committee]., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carlson, Laurette., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carlson, Lucille I., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carpenter, Ed., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carson, Charles., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Carus, Paul., 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1933-1951.; 9 items. (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1952-1958.; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1959-1964.; 15 items. (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1965.; 8 items. (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1966-1968.; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Caraman, Marya Tze, 1969-1971.; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Carlborg-Blades Incorporated., 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Carr, Harry, 1877-1936., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Carrington, Ulrich Steindorff, 1888-., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Carroll, Gladys Hasty, 1904-., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Carter, John, 1905-., 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Cas
    - Casanova (Booksellers)., 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Cash, Ben L., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Castleton, Chaffee King., 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Caxton Printers, 1951.; 7 items. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Caxton Printers, 1951-1957.; 12 items. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Caxton Printers, 1959.; 12 items. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Caxton Printers, 1959.; 10 items. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 9 items. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 13 items. (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 8 items. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 11 items. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 9 items. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960.; 5 items. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Caxton Printers, 1961-1970.; 9 items. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Caxton Printers, 1960-1969.; 23 items. Invoices. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1898-., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Ch - Ci
    - Charles Rare Books., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Child, T.A., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Christian, Shannon & Karen., 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Champion, Edouard Jean Marie, 1882-1938., 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Chandler, Norman F., 1899-., 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Chandler, Otis, 1927-., 3 items. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Chapin, Edward Young., 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chapin, Edward Young., 10 items. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chase, Mary Ellen., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Chattanooga, University of, 1945.; 10 items. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Chattanooga, University of, 1946-1949.; 16 items. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Chattanooga, University of, 1955-1957.; 11 items. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Chattanooga, University of, 1958-1960.; 10 items. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Chattanooga, University of, 1964-1966.; 4 items. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1907-n.d.; 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1934.; 11 items. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1934.; 9 items. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1935.; 5 items. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1937.; 7 items. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1938.; 6 items. (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1941.; 5 items. (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Cheney, William Murray, 1942-1964.; 8 items. (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - City Lights., 6 items. (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Cl
    - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer., 2 items. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clark, Jimmie., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clark, Sarah., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Arthur N. Clark Company., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Clemens, Cyril., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Cleveland News., 1 item. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Claremont Colleges., 9 items. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Claremont Colleges., 10 items. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Clary, William Webb, 1888-., 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Cleland, Robert Glass, 1885-1957., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Clough, Francis Gardner., 8 items. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Co - Con
    - Coast, Oscar R., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Coleman, Elizabeth R., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Collins, Ross., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Columbia University Press., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Combiths, Dess Bullard., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Conrath, Lionel B., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Conroy, Dorothy., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Cobb, Irvin Shrewsbury, 1876-1944., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Coblentz, Stanton Arthur, 1896-., 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Cochran, Louis, 1899-., 1953-1955.; 13 items. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Cochran, Louis, 1960-1964.; 12 items. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Cochran, Louis, 1965-1967.; 10 items. (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Cochran, Louis, 1968-1969.; 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Coffield, Glen, 1917-., 1 item (clipping). (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Colophon., 4 items. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Comfort, Will Levington, 1878-1932., 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Coo
    - Cook, C.V., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cornos, John., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Coverdale, Joan., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cowles, Thomas., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cox, J.M., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cox, Sidney., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Cooper, Madison A., 7 items. (Box 7, Folder 16a)
    - Cowan, Robert Ernest, 1862-1942., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Coward-McCann Incorporated., 3 items. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Cox, Kyle T. & Betsy, 1935-1960.; 13 items. (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Cox, Kyle T. & Betsy, 1961-1967.; 13 items. (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Cox, Kyle T. & Betsy, 1969-1970.; 8 items. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Cr - Cu
    - Crocker, Aileen., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Croessman, Dr. H.K., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Cunningham, Frank., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Curry, Margaret., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Curtis Brown Limited., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Crahan, Marcus Esketh., 1 item. (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Cronyn, George Williams, 1888-., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Croy, Homer, 1883-., 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Crummer, Dr. LeRoy, 1872-1934., 2 items. (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Crump, W.H.R., 6 items. (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Da
    - Danz, Louis., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Darby, Ada Claire., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Darst, Dr. H. Jackson., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Davis, J.W., 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Davis, Reuben., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-., 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Davey, Norman, 1888-., 13 items. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Davis, Harold Lenoir, 1896-., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Dawley, Grace, O., 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Dawson's Book Shop., 5 items. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - De
    - de Farnaro, C., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - de Filippi, Almedeo., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - de Heustamont, Margaret L., 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - De Jugen, Dorothy., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Dennis, Phyllis Forbes., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Devaré, Ulric., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - DeCasseres, Benjamin, 1873-1945., 11 items. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - DeCasseres, Benjamin., 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1887-., n.d.- 1924.; 10 items. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1925.; 11 items. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1926.; 6 items. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1927.; 14 items. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Dell, Floyd, 1927-1937.; 10 items. (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Dewey, Nicholas., 8 items. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Di
    - Dickinson, Pearl & Winfield., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Didway, Charles., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Dial Press., 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Dick, Hugh Gilchrist, 1909-., 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Dodge, Louis, 1870-., 1934-1936.; 7 items. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Dodge, Louis, 1937-1939.; 11 items. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Dodge, Louis, 1940-1945.; 9 items. (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Doheny, Estelle (Betzold)., 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Do - Du
    - Doane, Gilbert., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Dodd, Mead & Company., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Donahue, Freda Kathleen., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - George H. Doran Company., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Dowdev, Clifford., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Downes, Carl S., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Dunkel, John., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Dunlap, Elizabeth Hawley., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1944-1960.; 14 items. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1961.; 32 items. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1962.; 18 items. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Doubleday & Company, 1963-1970.; 12 items. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Dowing, J. Hyatt, 1938-1962.; 9 items. (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Dowing, J. Hyatt, 1963-1965.; 13 items. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Downing, J. Hyatt, 1966-1967.; 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - (1) Letter from Theodore Dreiser to karl Fischer. Hollywood, California, March 7, 1940.; 2 leaves, typescript copy. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - (2) Letter from Helen Dreiser to Paul Jordan Smith. Hollywood, California, February 27, 1946.; 1 leaf, typescript. (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - (3) Crawford, Bruce. "Theodore Dreiser Letter-writing citizen". Reprinted from the South Atlantic Quarterly, vol.53 no.2, April 1954.; pp.[231]-237. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Dubin, Martin David., 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Dunn, Waldo Hilary, 1882-., 6 items. (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Durant, William James, 1885-., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - E.P. Dutton Company, Incorporated., 2 items. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Dyer, Brainerd, 1901-., 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - E - Ek
    - Ebell Club, Los Angeles., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Eckerson, Olive., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Eddy, Frederick S., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Editor Magazine., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Earle, Homer Price., 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Eastman, Max, 1883-1969., 10 items. (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Eastman, Max., 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Edwards, Ward., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - El - Ez
    - Elkin Mathews Limited., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Elliot, Barbara., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Ellis, Edward F., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Ende, Clara von., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Epstein, Dave A., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Evans, William H., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Ewington, Alfred Duffy., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Eldridge, Paul., 12 items. (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Ellis, Charlotte., 7 items. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1859-1939., 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Elwood, Irene., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Emory & Henry College., 14 items. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Evans, Montgomery, n.d.-1943.; 11 items. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Evans, Montgomery, 1944-1948.; 11 items. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Evans, Montgomery, 1951-1954.; 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Ewing, Majl, 1903-., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Fa - Fe
    - Fantasy Advertiser., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Farnsworth, Irene., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Fatout, Paul., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Fawcett World Library., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Frederick W. Fell Incorporated., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Fenlon, Ruth., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Farrar & Rinehart., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Fernandes-Camacho, Reverend J.E., 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Feuchtwanger, Marta., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Fi - Fl
    - Field, Sarah Bard., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Filardi, Tom., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - First Unitarian Church., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Fisher, Louise N., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Fitch, Robert E., 3 items. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Fletcher, Inglis (Clark), 1888-., 5 items. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Fischer, Hanns, n.d.-1965.; 11 items. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Fischer, Hanns, 1966-1969.; 14 items. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Fisher, Mary Frances (Kennedy), 1908-., 2 items. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Fisher, Vardis, 1895-., 14 items. (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Fo
    - Fodor, M.W., 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 25)